all right let's see if this is going to
work
i hate when they change things all right
hello try mod view what's mod view
the sword below to get started
mod view oh this seems too complicated
for me
don't they know i'm an idiot oh my god
and i hate these click-through tutorials
i'm sorry you guys aren't seeing this
this is too hard
this is way too hard oh no i want the
old thing back
please please go back can you all hear
me
i got a decent quality microphone
um cool
hello
i don't got to stream more trust me
don't look to me for inspiration
don't ever make nobody your hero man
they're only going to let you down
except for the cast
mike too low all right we can crank that
let's crank that soldier boy you know
all right let's see what we got here
crank that
soldier boy soldier blow up in the hole
climbing crank it why me
is that better all right
hello yo yo that's nice all right i'm
glad you're happy
we don't have a happy hacking keyboard
today i know you're all going to ask we
got this guy
it's a little too large for my liking
but we do have a matching uh
rest thingy um can i find a bulgaria on
a map
um yeah so
let me think about that i mean it's over
by like here's ukraine
estonia latvia bulgaria
did i get that right
oops estonia latvia bulgaria i'll go
with that
we'll see if i'm right
um estonia latvia oh bola ruse
okay sorry i got belarus and bulgaria
mixed up well gary is the one below
romania
oh well
um they're both b countries you know
what i'm saying
you know what i'm saying bros all right
i'm a map new right
um
let's minimize that
okay belarus is the cleanest country
i look i need a visa for belarus right
like i want to do a trip i want to do a
uh
i want to do a trip around here but um
no we are here today to talk about
coronavirus
i have a few props prepared for
everybody too i worked i put a lot of
effort into this stream
so one thing that i'm going to reiterate
multiple times
this this is a surgical mask it does
absolutely nothing to prevent the spread
of coronavirus
um after 30 minutes these things are
just damp saturated
you're breathing in the same number of
air i am definitely
with the birthday party those in the
birthday party know what that means
this does nothing this is dumb as
anybody who's advocating the wearing of
these masks is a moron
this is a virtue signaling device and
should be referred to as a face
diaper even dumber than this and i don't
even own one because it's dumber and
does even less is a cloth mask
if you'd like to prevent coronavirus now
this again is only going to prevent
you from getting it it's not going to
prevent you from spreading it because it
has a different n95 masks do this too
it has a separate intake path from
exhalation path
so the intake goes through this yeah
this is a face
diaper i don't wear diapers on my ass
and i do not wear diapers
no the masks are not better than nothing
the masks do nothing
and you have to be uncomfortable and
wear a stupid mask
well they remind people of the pandemic
no
um i mean this is just one of the
biggest pieces
of misinformation i've seen online about
coronavirus
remember how they didn't recommend masks
in the beginning
because the truth is well so even
stupider than a surgical mask
they're not better than nothing well
okay this may be better than nothing
but what's not better than nothing is a
cloth mask
see this this is a pair of boxers right
this is effectively what a cloth mask is
made out of
i can see the holes in it you can see
holes
does nothing a cloth mask does
absolutely nothing and it's probably not
it probably is not better than nothing
because people think they're safe are
wearing these things
so for reference extremely stupid
quite stupid now let's get into what's
actually
effective
a respirator all right oops my
respirator fell apart it obviously is
less effective if it falls apart
but this thing and n95
masks to a lesser extent
um no not better than this and i really
hate that it's become it's a stupid
political thing
this is a scientific question it can be
asked scientifically
this will prevent you from getting
coronavirus now
this will not prevent you from spreading
coronavirus
so if you'll notice the way this thing
is designed
the operating room is designed to
prevent spit not to prevent uh
microscopic virus particulates um
the eyes are not as big of a it is
largely through breath now
be aware looking at this mask um this
is the intake and this is the exhalation
so when i exhale using this mask there's
actually a one-way valve in here
you'll see
right um i will update
i will update if anybody can show
conclusive evidence
about the effectiveness of this or this
i do not believe that either of these
are effective at all
and i am almost sure in fact if you look
at a package of cloth masks
um i bought a package of cloth masks i
wish i had the package
um it said very clearly on the package
does nothing to prevent the spread of
viruses
these things are virtue signaling
devices and honestly look
it's not a political thing for me i
don't like being forced into other
people's religion
right um
here uh
there are not good studies on masks
because they're kind of hard to do and i
have locked
um and we'll look into we'll get into
studies in a minute but here
right
oh yeah no if you really want the uh
if you really want the mask that's
effective get the this that also
includes the face shield
if you get that that covers your eyes
that's going to prevent the spread of
coronavirus
viral droplets i have not seen evidence
that the virus is in
droplets either the cloth masks do
nothing to prevent either inhalation or
exhalation you can literally see the
holes this is a pair of calvin klein
boxers it's made the same thing as cloth
masks
um so you know if there's anything to
take away from this
let's let's do it let's see part of the
problem and we've talked about this
before is that a lot of the studies
right now
if you find a study on masks well you
know
it's it's the global warming problem
right
if global warming is not a thing you
wouldn't know it
because there's one quote unquote
scientific consensus if you publish a
article now on uh if you publish an
article saying you know global warming
is not not a scam but you know not as
bad as people think
you're not going to get funding from the
nih right uh funding from the you know
national science foundation or who's
ever who's ever given out grants for
these things right
it's gonna be the same thing with the uh
the nih and coronavirus you come out
with a study be like
you know masks aren't really that useful
well you're not getting funding again
um if i think the virus isn't in
droplets well
my understanding is the virus is mostly
produced in the lungs
my argument against the virus being in
droplets is
if it was in droplets and spit why is
the test not spinning a cup
why do they have to take a a swab and
stick it six inches up your nose
um like it's it's my point is once
things become politicized it's very
difficult to get any sort of real
information on them
now that said there have been some good
studies on
the different uh treatments
so if we go back to this is my
coronavirus repo on github
um i listed a few potential uh
treatments back in the day um
hydroxychloroquinolone plus zinc uh
we'll get to we'll get to that one later
again unfortunately that one became
politicized
and it's very hard to get any real
information
um on that but i think the more
interesting one is remdesseviere
um so remdesavir is a
uh adenosine analog meaning that i
believe it's the adenosine and rna
actually
rna uses the same adenosine as dna i
believe
it's just they don't use thiamine they
use uracil
no not everything is political in
america everything is political on the
american news
the most part of america hates politics
um politics is
at least historically when i grew up is
like a bad word in america
once something's politicized you get you
get bias
right um now this is not this is not one
side of the political spectrum
uh everyone involved in politics in
america does this
um even you know we'll rip on someone no
one cares about like libertarians
um if libertarians came out you know if
there was a study that showed that uh
fiat money actually
promotes economic growth more than uh
having a gold standard
don't publish that study man don't
publish that study we got to get back on
gold um
[Music]
so you're taking a mouth swab test again
it's a scraping swab it's not a spit
test right yeah ron
paul 2008 man ron paul 2012 i remember
that
ron paul revel love lucian dexmethazone
yeah yeah so we're going to look into
dexamethasone as well
um we're going to look into so i've seen
basically three things come out and they
all work differently
so there's hydroxychloroquinolone um
there's uh remdessevere and there's
dexamethasone
so let's look into studies for all three
of those
and i seem biased toward presuming the
mass perspective is foolish with what
um so let's let's look at ramdas of our
studies
so things that we're looking for in
studies that are good
is we want studies that are double blind
and we want studies that are large
um so double blind means that
neither the patients nor the
experimenters know who's in which group
um obviously they have the control group
and the experimental group
this basic science 101 um your control
group receives a placebo
uh your experimental group receives the
drug and then
nobody knows until after the study is
over
um who's in which group so you can
record everything you don't want the
experimenters to know because they might
be
biased you obviously don't want the
people to know because the placebo
effect is quite real
um so that's what we're looking for in
studies double blind large sample size
and reasonable thing tracked um so
another thing to look for in studies too
and we'll see if we can find any
evidence of this is pre-registration
uh yeah we can zoom in um
so pre-registration means that they said
what they were going to find
before they did the study
uh so i think the uk uk
covid studies i forget what it was
called i i heard about this
um
uk mega trial yeah uk mega trial called
recovery
i liked the way they were doing this
um they had a website
sorry i'm not i'm not as fluid this is
my new desk for me so
i can't make a trial recovery i'm going
to be a little slower on the computer
oh here we go yes yeah it's recovery
trial.net
um my god i hate my
results here we go okay so
oh this wasn't the one the texts that
tested um
remdesseviere but let's check out their
dex methods on study
[Music]
uh published on met archive so met
archive is like the uh
it's i believe it's the open access
journal
for medicine all right so let's read
this study
uh so first off some basics on death
methazone my understanding is it's
steroid
um corticosteroid uh
now something to note about all
corticosteroids
is that they block the immune system and
they're also anti-inflammatory
so if you're familiar with a drug like
ibuprofen
ibuprofen is an nsab it's a
non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drug
i think all steroids are both
anti-inflammatory
and immunosuppressant but i'm not 100
on that um but i know it's true about
dexmethozone
okay
so dexmethazone is corticosteroid
equals anti-inflammatory
plus immunosuppressant
now let's look at the study
background damage corticosteroids
modulate immune mediated lung
injury immune media so basically
um when they talk about the cytokine
storm at the end of coronavirus
uh you have that's being done largely i
believe by your immune system and this
is ending up doing more damage than the
virus so if we can suppress the immune
system
people might um
live longer okay so
[Music]
randomly allocates and i don't like this
randomized controlled open label what
does open label mean
i don't see double blind in there
wait what with both the health care
providers
and the patients are aware of the drug
or treatment being given
okay that's not great
um
randomly allocated
allocated to usual care so this is
another problem too
it's not this isn't a placebo study at
all never mind i thought these studies
were good
um it is large though so that's good
and the primary outcome was 28 day
mortality so i like that as an outcome
basically how many people died
oh did it freeze
what
we turn off wi-fi make sure
no wi-fi are we live it's back now
i don't know
okay cool we live alright good good
is the stream overall high quality no
it's working fine good
um okay conclusions and patients
hospitalized with covid reduced
28-day mortality among those receiving
invasive
but not among patients not receiving
respiratory support
so i i i heard this too and it's like
the question i have here
is i mean whether they receive
ventilation or don't receive ventilation
already puts them in like two completely
different classes of patient
investigators analysis open label
i mean some of the other problems you
can't do all drugs
with uh control versus non-control
because i think you can
i think you're aware whether you're
taking steroids or not i don't know
i've never taken it never take this down
right
i'm also are these the same as like are
anabolic steroids something different
synthetic testosterone testosterone
is an anti-inflammatory and
anabolic steroid
[Music]
immune system can be damaged but they
don't talk
and the word inflammatory doesn't appear
here at all interesting so steroids may
refer to different things like what does
a steroid actually mean
[Music]
oh huh
it has to do with these rings
got like one of those pyrimidine rings
right
no i guess pyrimidine has two nitrogens
never mind i don't know what i'm saying
don't listen to me
there we go dexton okay so that's what
dexamethasone looks like compared to
testosterone
they're not pyrimidine rings yeah i know
sorry i don't remember chemistry guys
um
all right for some new people who got on
this is a mask
this prevents you from getting
coronavirus not as good as a mask that
also covers your eyes
this is a face diaper it makes you look
stupid and doesn't really do anything
else
here's another thing no known indication
or contraindication like what is that
if the contraindication is something
well i guess they weren't included right
so they weren't included in the sample
so that's fine
you have to be really careful with all
this stuff because these effects are
pretty small
their final outcome of the study showed
like
reduced deaths by one-third receiving
invasive mechanical
ventilation what's the actual
number
95 percent confidence interval
p-values man p-values
there's like a better way what replaces
p-values
no this definitely doesn't reduce your
chance by 60 let's even say it blocks 60
of particles blocking 60 of particles
does not reduce your chance 60 percent
of getting the virus
obviously right
um well we can ask that question too
what's the difference in the us and the
european countries that did much better
are we 100 percent sure that they
actually did better
um so
here here's an interesting
um the united states is out testing
everybody
like all of the not everybody i think i
think iceland beats the united states
um but
i mean let's say that let's even just
talk about the false positive rate of
the test and i don't think this is true
i think you can control for this pretty
well statistically but if a test has a
one percent false positive rate
and we're doing two tests for every
thousand people
well two tests for every thousand people
says 300 million people in america so
we're testing 0.2 percent of the
population
so 300 times 0.2 percent um
0.2 percent so
um it's 0.6 million so we're text we're
testing 600 thousand people
a day right if this test rate has a one
percent false positive rate
then we're going to expect six thousand
cases of coronavirus a day that aren't
real cases of coronavirus
um now i'm not exactly sure this is true
what is the daily cases per day
i still like this tracker
we can ask the strain hypothesis too
okay the daily cases are
so we'd expect 10 of these well we
should actually look up what's the false
positive rate of the test
and which test they're doing
i can just find something generic if the
antibody tests have a lot of false
positives i know i think the rtpcr test
doesn't have too many
um also an interesting
saying you can't find any trustworthy
scientific note on us work on a subject
once it becomes politicized as a fallacy
no i didn't say that
but it says it's harder to right but
there's some things that are going to be
really hard to find
like i think you'd be very hard to find
a mask study because that's a hard thing
to study right
when you're looking at a test like this
on a drug where it's it's large and
hopefully double blind
um so this is the dexamethasone study
seems to have effects in late stage
which would make sense blocking
immune response
um let's find that rim death severe
study this is what got me interested in
this again because from death severe
actually looks good
um now we have a bias here with
remdesseviere remember gilead
has a big financial incentive and i mean
this i found interesting
how has this not gone up right
i mean i'm i'm tempted to buy gilead uh
gilead stock because well we'll get to
that later and i don't own any gilead
stock full disclosure you know i don't i
don't make any money off you doing yet
i think it was this study here
um i get a pdf version here we go
so okay a few cool things about this
study
double-blind randomized
placebo-controlled trial
of intravenous from death severe and
adults hospitalized with
cover 19 with evidence of lower
respiratory tract infection
patients were randomly assigned to
receive either the remdessevier
or the placebo their their primary
outcome i don't like
and i want to see if they pre-registered
this or not right because this could be
a thing where
you you really i like the 28-day death
number a whole lot better
maybe we can find it in the study and do
our own statistics on it
but a total of a thousand patients
underwent randomization
um the data and safety monitoring board
recommended
early unblinding of the results okay i
don't like that
early on blinding
when
um
mean recovery time of 11 days is
compared with 15 days
meyer estimates of mortality now i don't
know why they couldn't just use real
real uh mortality here
but this is significant 7.1 versus 11.9
you know i shouldn't say words like this
is significant it seems significant
rate ratio for recovery i don't know
that term
[Music]
this has nothing to do with that
let's see if we can find clinical trials
was this pre-registered
what i'm trying to find out is was this
here the pre-registered thing or did
they
say that after they got the data
um by the way for some fun reference on
room destivier
um rem desavier is a pro drug
for the uh the adenosine analog
[Music]
uh so it's a pro drug designed to allow
intercellular delivery of this
which also apparently is a drug as well
you may not need the pro drug so you can
compare it to like vivants versus
adderall i don't know that's my only
real uh
that that is a thing you know about i
know about pro drugs and then
what's the
[Music]
i addre that's true pro-drug
primarily in viva which means in within
the living
to modafinil um
i don't know i know things about illegal
drugs i'm not a doctor man
we hate bill gates get out of here get
out of here no political
i mean we all hated windows but you know
yeah we could we not
um no one thing i do say about the hoax
is there's two coronaviruses going
around uh the first coronavirus is
coveted 19 sars cop2 it has a dna
sequence
it causes respiratory infection it
causes cough it causes fever
on the other one is coronavirus with a
capital c
it causes people to panic shut down
restaurants and wear diapers on their
face right
one of these is a scam one of these is a
real disease
um us versus europe we can get to u.s
versus europe
um something i've noticed in the u.s
press
is it depends where you're getting this
from but hatred for the united states is
quite trendy
so like again
is there is there truth to this and then
what do you mean by europe right
is the us doing worse than italy or
spain or are you comparing it to
countries like iceland and uh you know
denmark and stuff
um oh yes capital c coronavirus is
definitely producing real symptoms
i think capital c coronas can cause
capital c
coronavirus uh i think it's associated
with a higher rate of suicide
um i think it's so associated with a
higher rate of um
depression anxiety it's really a mental
health condition it's contagious too
it's spread to all countries uh it
spreads at the speed of information
in order to be infected all you have to
do is uh is read the propaganda on the
internet
um face
diaper why are there no new spikes in
europe well
so it's interesting to note about the
spikes in america
uh so i'm actually i'm in new jersey
right now um
you can't view the united states is a
very large country the united states is
really similar to
to all of europe i think it's actually
population of the eu
okay so it's a bit larger than america
um
let's do land area of eu
okay so the united states is about twice
as physically large
europe has 50 more people um so united
states again is it's many different
places
uh if you look at new york um there's no
spike
right um
if you look at new york it looks like
this if you look at california
it looks like this um by the way
what this really shows to me also and i
talked about this at the end of last
stream is
why did california do a lockdown when
things looked like this
it was incredibly stupid and now when
you might want to consider a lockdown
there is much less uh political support
for that
because you kept people locked down for
absolute
in new york there was a lockdown
starting here at the peak of a spike and
well you know now it looks like that
i'm so new jersey looks similar to new
york it's almost called the identical
trajectory
where texas and florida look a whole lot
more
like well california's been steady up
the whole time florida and texas have
seen spikes
on new jersey and new york have seen no
second wave and illinois has started to
see a second wave
i'm not trolling about masks uh so
face diapers there's some evidence maybe
for
um but there is absolutely zero evidence
for cloth masks
which do nothing i can literally see you
guys i can read the chat
um look at india's graph through this
quote-unquote cloth mask
i don't have one sorry it's a pair of
boxers uh
but cloth masks do absolutely nothing
and they're they're it's like wearing a
cross around your neck and saying i wear
this cross around my neck to prevent
coronavirus
again you want to do that that's fine
don't tell me i gotta wear a cross i
don't believe in your fake god
um
check out this about cloth masks all
right again only real study please don't
link me to any conspiracy theory
websites
uh visualizing speech generated oral
fluid droplets so
um this again this isn't a mask study
right do masks make the air go less far
well obviously yes right you can you can
do this with the sim you can do this
study with the simplest stuff
but it doesn't change the total volume
of air
that's been uh breathed out right so
even if the air goes slightly less far
right like what if there's a tiny wind
a tiny wind cancels out the mask right
most air is not that stagnant
um this is not a mass study if somebody
would like to show me a controlled mask
study
i'd be happy to read it and analyze it
here and you know what look guys i'm a
scientist
i would if you guys show me evidence for
this i'll change my mind
um but this is the one as far as i can
tell
i also find the more again this is my
same problem with with with
uh a lot of the rhetoric around global
warming um
they they say that if you don't believe
this you're a bad person
if you don't wear a mask you're killing
people like
if you have to use that rhetoric i think
you don't actually have science on your
side i think you're using this rhetoric
um let's also let's let's look into this
for a little bit is this a p95
respirator
um by the way this also doesn't apply to
n95 masks
i think there's definitely at least some
evidence for n95 masks
preventing you from getting coronavirus
i'm specifically railing against face
diapers
um a p95 mask
yeah p95 mask
what's the difference in a p95 and n95
does not protect against oily particles
uh yeah i don't think coronavirus is an
oily particle
oh well this is the other thing too
about how long these masks last
and whether people are changing them and
disposing of them properly
this thing will last a long time um i
climbed down a
a volcano in uh in indonesia
um and this is all there's all sulfur at
the bottom of the volcano and i was
wearing a gas mask not a good one i
rented it in indonesia
and it slipped off my face a little bit
i took in a breath of that stuff
oh my god um so
a p100 what's a 100
oh yeah now we're talking
and this might this might be a p100 well
see if we can find any evidence
any words on it organic vapers
3m i actually bought this for allergies
that's very effective against allergies
3m part number 501 this doesn't seem to
have a model number on it
oh wait is p200 a real thing
no but i mean yeah the other problem
with these things is
while it may filter the air you breathe
it does not filter any of the air you
breathe out
um no so uh association of country-wide
mortality with mask wearing
means absolutely nothing that's that's a
completely uncontrolled study
the problem is people who are more
compliant in masks are probably also
more compliant social distancing
social distancing pretty obviously uh
works
they're not like i don't know about six
feet versus but let me tell you if
you're in a different house from
somebody else
yes chronovirus doesn't spread between
houses
um this works great for i'm allergic to
something in new jersey or
something in this house and uh this
works great for that
and 95 is the threshold for masks
working i would believe that
i would believe that um okay let's take
a look in uh at rim destiny
i mean always remember if somebody ever
tries to tell you that you're a bad
person
for not believing in some science it's
probably because that science is
questionable
they won't resort to it if it's true
nobody tells you you're a bad person for
not believing two plus two equals four
okay um so again we have to look for
by one one of the big concerns about
bias here
is remdesseviere is a it's still
patented by gilead pharmaceuticals
so it's success means monetary success
so
um
i'm gonna adapt a platform to rapidly
conduct a series of phase
three let's just look up fda phase three
what's phase three mean
phase three are random controlled
multi-center
oh well that's cool
uh yeah that'd be nice that's something
else we should look for i mean because
remember
if it's double if it's truly
double-blind and they follow good
double-blind protocols
then this probably is less of a problem
but yeah i mean there could also be
something else so i like that it's like
keeping your data in multiple data
centers
uh phase three trial is the most
expensive time consuming difficult to
run
especially for chronic um
enrollment oh there were 60 trial sites
in the united states
uh
so what a written policy for use on
other treatments
before enrollment in the trial
i see i like this
missed doses intermittently how this is
iv for hospitalized people how did they
miss doses
um why would i
well i mean i guess it kind of says
something but
this is i mean this is just interesting
in and of itself
64 male
patients receiving oxygen proportion
recovered
so i mean just just just looking at this
off the top of my head though it does
get kind of small it seems like rim
deserver is the most
uh effective for patients receiving
oxygen but once you're
here it doesn't do all that much which
is it's interesting that
i mean i'm going to guess right now that
i think the
normal course of treatment is going to
look like rim desevere early on
and then once you're going on high flow
oxygen dexamethasone to knock out your
immune system
cumulative recovery estimate so why are
they using these estimates and why are
they not using just
true recovery
number of recoveries but number of
recoveries over what
time horizon
to unblind the results to the trial team
members
i'm always i'm always concerned when i
see this
even though the trial was ongoing the
data and safety monitoring board made
the recommendation to unblind the
results
who subsequently decided to make the
results public given the strength of the
results these findings were deemed to be
of immediate importance for the care of
the patients
that's not scientific language that's
political language and whenever i see
that remember
politics doesn't have anything to do
with party politics it can also be
corporate politics
right it can also be gileads trying to
fast-track this and sell a hundred
thousand doses to the state of louisiana
or something right
given the high mortality rate despite
the use of industries it's clear the
treatment with an antiviral drug alone
is not likely to be sufficient
it's finding support we're hospitalized
and require additional oxygen therapy
i mean this is interesting to note as
well like i wonder
also there's a treatment for the flu and
we should look into how this one works
tamiflu
so tamiflu i think is fda approved to
actually shorten
the uh the duration of the flu which
seems like it's behaving
similarly to remdessevier for covet but
let's figure out how this one works
oh never mind concludes that it does not
reduce hospitalization there's no
evidence of reduction of
complications okay maybe this stuff
doesn't work
um yeah and this this works it's a
completely different uh
mechanism too
nerimidase so i don't think uh
i mean if you guys watch my other
streams
i don't think there there's any remedies
in coronavirus
um we did a whole lot of reading
uh
remember here's oh here's all the uh the
proteins that are in coronavirus from
the last streams
and like you know it pretty well now
there's uh i don't think chronovirus has
this one of the biggest things that it
has one of the things that it spends
most of its um room coding for
is rna-dependent rna polymerase which i
think is relatively a large part of the
dna
i mean look at the size of that protein
man
huh from there no chronovirus isn't
there they give all these viruses stupid
multi-letter names
so i i so also remdesavir back in the
day i remember it showed the highest
uh highest binding affinity
uh they did these these computer
simulations they just remember something
about investigating 13.
all right since we got some new people
in here just a quick reminder
this is a face diaper
this is a mask and this is a piece of
cloth
full of large holes which does nothing
to prevent the spread of coronavirus
if you want to prevent the spread of
coronavirus wear a
mask
[Music]
so i'm not so sure the droplets thing
means means anything at all um
this virus replicates in your lungs
there's no water in your lungs
do i wear this thing when going out no i
do the absolute minimum required i'm not
personally afraid of getting this at all
i do the absolute minimum required to
not make people feel too uncomfortable
ah what is this about shingles
treatment for shingles
uh well so these are so these these
these other
uh cyclovirs i mean these are aids drugs
and herpes drugs too
um how do these ones work i probably
looked this up last time
inhibits and inactivates dna polymerases
it prevents replication so so this um
remdessever uh prevents
so when it's replicating i think it uses
these fake adenosines in the rna
i'm not a hundred percent sure on this
we can look into this a little bit
um
in nuclear ribonucleotide analogs
okay i'm guessing there's not
oh azt this is another this is another
common aids drug
affimidine all right so this is the t so
rna doesn't have t
right rna uses uracil instead of thymine
i can't spell sorry
uh yeah
huh most of the words feminine
production
you can take
oh they use thiamidine to produce this
oh yeah look they just replaced the uh
bboh group with uh what's an oh group is
this an alcohol
oh group is an alcohol
i'm sorry my internet glitched for a
second
hydroxyl it's a hydroxyl group saying oh
my god see i should know this um
i mean ethanol has a hydroxyl group so
what's the alcohol group
like that that's a hydroxyl group and
ethanol linked to a hydroxyl
that carries at least one hydroxyl
functional group bound to a saturated
carbon atom so what does saturated mean
i mean i guess
this would be saturated right because it
has a hydrogen
and so you have saturated yeah like
saturated saturated fats of single
carbon bonds the unsaturated have double
carbon bonds
um okay let's look into
hydroxychloroquine now
when i looked at hydroxychloroquine last
time um
what i found is that we would not expect
it
to yes saturates no double bonds uh we
don't talk about politics in here please
cut all the politics talk
um you could talk about politics on the
meta level talking about politics on the
object level
is not welcome um
so yeah let's look into hydroxychloric
now we would not
expect it to be effective on its own
because what we looked into last time is
chloroquine is a zinc ionopore
the hydroxychloroquine just lets the
zinc into the cell
which lowers the uh which which makes
this stuff not work as well
so if the virus can't replicate you do
not get more
virus um so i think that no i like that
uk
study now less because it is an open
trial was that their term for it they
had a term i should i should know these
terms you know if you want to get good
in a field you should memorize their
terms
um recovery trial here we go
recoverychild.net that's it
uh let's oh yeah she's looking at the
terminals open label
open label um
so let's look at their
hydroxychloroquine study
no benefit
did they also receive zinc or did they
just receive
hydroxychloroquine and why is there not
a paper for this one
dexmethazones on there oh yeah and then
ratanavir they found no benefit for this
let's look at how this one works
this is like an aids cocktail right
protease inhibitor
it's a protease
oh the cleaving oh okay
i remember that how's this one work
booster inhibits hiv protease
yeah i'm not sure why people would
expect this to work for growtovirus
um
we could really i'm thinking like we
should dive back into it to see if like
now with this new information like does
coronavirus have a protease
um does it have that other uh
but yeah i'm not surprised that that one
didn't work
because we don't have well we just did
have some proteases right
springs back up replicase
poly protein
poppy and like protease
so this is what's doing the the cleaving
damn you know i gotta you always gotta
comment your code better i wrote this
code a while ago
um
but yeah so this is the the replication
machinery
this thing has a bunch of proteins
or f1 and f1b formula replication
there's the exploit vector which is the
spike um
i don't know what that does
the envelope and the membrane
and then the capsid
all right so that's
that's the air oh yeah we're looking at
the hydroxychloroquine
why don't we have a paper for this one
policy political trash
retracted a paper that said it increased
death risk i'm great they put the word
why did they retract it
[Music]
you have to use zinc as well so that's
the study i want to find you guys find
any studies
yeah we checked out room designer and
death severe is the first one we checked
out
uh well no we first checked out
dexamethasone
but i'm bullish on rim december i think
it definitely has a real effect
um i don't want any political stuff if
you guys can show me a
a actual i'm looking for what i'm
looking for is a large
double-blind randomized study on
hydroxychloroquine
plus zinc
it's a marcos i'm looking at you
now so here this is
yeah okay so this is showing that
without zinc it doesn't work which is
exactly what we'd expect
there was a uh yeah a chloroquine and a
zinc ionopore
so alone neither hydroxychloroquine or
zinc work
but what hydroxychloroquine allows zinc
into the cell and then once it's in the
cell it blocks
rna-dependent rna polymerase um
so let's see when did this come out may
take a look at this well first
this is not a study at all this is just
looking at data
ah there could be so many other
confounding factors there
i don't like this can we find a good
study
all right we got clinical trials here
a study of hydroxychloroquine and the
prevention of covid
in
multicenter oh oh compared to okay
okay this is good
did this study come out yet estimated
study completion date july 31st so it's
not out yet
we have information
this website's cool clinicaltrials.gov
show me all the clinical trials i wish
they had like a trending clinical trials
i could see what like cool new drugs
there are
listed clinical studies related to
coronavirus
oh you can you can sign up for them
oh that's pretty cool i can get
infloxable if i go up to tufts
what's in fleximab
chimeric monoclonal okay i don't really
know that much about monoclonal
antibodies we are going to spend a
little time looking into the viability
of a vaccine
um my initial just like common sense
take on that
is people looked for a long time for a
vaccine for car
sars the vaccine for the flu is very hit
or miss
um so i am bearish on a vaccine i'm
bullish
on remdesseviere and things that look
like it
um you know usually this is a my
understanding is this is a relatively
new uh drug class
um antivirals have have helped against
all sorts of antivirals of this you know
everyone knows about antibiotics
but there are antivirals that work um
i don't want to hear you know you people
argue about sweden and like oh sweden
did this oh it looks like this it looks
like that
is it 10x if it's not 10x i don't want
to hear 40 percent
you know what does that mean that your
can get you can come from so many
different factors
there was another study talking about
different blood types and whether you
die or not and i'm like yeah but you
understand blood type is like there's so
many
other inputs into what your blood type
is blood types are not randomly
distributed through the population
um i you know the the the amount of of
pseudoscience and stupidity
uh that that that goes around and then
and then you know
the the the worst part of something
becoming politicized
is people will accept a statement
dogmatically and then
like i said will i stop calling these
fake
face diapers and become an advocate for
wearing them yes when you show me a
study
right i haven't seen any studies um
and i think the the mechanism isn't
there right but you you
people will just say things and you ask
them like what evidence do you have to
back that up and they have no idea
it's it's it's it's infuriating like my
statement about security is always this
it's best to have security and know you
have security it's second best to not
have security and know you don't have
security
it's worse to not have security but know
you have security
and it's the same way with knowledge
right it's best to have knowledge and
know you have knowledge it's second best
to not have knowledge and know you don't
have knowledge
but if you don't have knowledge and know
you have knowledge
that's that's how idiocy spreads
it doesn't protect you but protect the
other
very unclear so even 95 masks don't do
that even this is like a p95
i think this might be a p100 actually
let's look this up i found the number
it's a 3m 6001
oh that's just a cartridge
organic vapor even this mask it doesn't
protect the other it only protects you
this is a one-way valve so when you
breathe out all the air just goes right
out
you breathe in it's through here
what about caution no what about caution
well you know
why don't wear a cross around your neck
cross won't kill you
maybe it'll save others right don't push
your religion on me
um
[Music]
all right what do we got we got some
studies coming in let's see what we got
thank you team google
how can i say there's no studies let's
see what the study is
[Music]
uh
okay all right all right all right we
will read the study let's see what we
got
surgical masks
so
so okay let's let's let's so first off
good things about this study
it's it's a mass study it came out in
2008 before there was any uh political
stuff associated with it
so this is probably uh a good study now
again they did things where they were
showing
um
this they're using a model they're
they're not actually you know they don't
have a control group
you want to see studies so first off you
can't do a double blind that asks that
um the problem is it's very obvious
who's wearing a mask and who's not
wearing a mask
what you'd want to do is if you could
figure out how to make some masks
effective and some masks ineffective
distribute them randomly
see who gets the disease and who doesn't
right that would be that would be a real
study on this
oh no
[Music]
influenza can be transmitted through
three major routes large droplets
does influenza replicate in the lungs
where does it replicate
this is the whole cell but is it is it
lung cells or is it
alveolar epithelial cells
all right so yeah the lungs house okay
cool
so probably similar stuff
a large droplet and direct indirect
contact
zuck wife looks like she eats children
for dinner
consider using duck.gov no i'll continue
to use google
um i thought about it but sucks more and
it's going subscriber only because
people saying real dumb
a reduction factor of around six can be
anticipated
so do we have a study on how much
reduction factor
uh
links to action that's just a reduction
in the factor of the number of particles
what's an ffp respirator
um you know unfortunately uh
one of my favorite blogs has been taken
off the internet
um
but i think they he had a truthful uh
this is this is where i first heard
about masks
also i hear archive.org is under attack
because of some book copyright thing so
you know make me very sad if that goes
away
if there's anything i can do to prevent
it
um
so this is this is this is written
before there was anything political
um and i trust this guy's thinking on a
lot of stuff he's he's a doctor
ah
if people with masks risk compensate
even a few
uh percent an np or r rated respirator
worn properly in specific high risk
situations can be an appropriate part of
a safety strategy
i absolutely agree with that i think an
accurate treatment of the topic would
admit this
while also stressing the reasons that
most masks might not appropriate
uh might reasons most masks might not
a pro be appropriate i guess for most
people in most situations
so
uh right now we're talking i mean my my
opinion on on masks
is uh cloth masks do absolutely nothing
to prevent the virus and
it drives me crazy that all of these
stores now put up some signs saying you
have to wear a cloth mask
right um i really don't like things
that look like this that look like so
it's best to have security and know you
have security
it's second best to not have security
and know you don't have security
but it's the worst to not have security
but know you have security
right and this is what things like cloth
masks do which don't block
anything but they give people a false
sense of security and you know
i i just i really hate things that look
like that um these face diapers
there's a little bit more evidence for
them but
again yeah sure if you wore a new one
you changed it every 30 minutes and you
used it perfectly maybe you'd get
something um but i think overall again
like stop giving people a false sense of
security with this crap if you want to
be serious
about wearing a mask to prevent
coronavirus and again this doesn't
prevent your spread of coronavirus
this prevents you from getting
coronavirus
um it has a different intake and
exhalation route
but if you walk around wearing one of
these all day you're not only not going
to get coronavirus you're probably not
going to get a whole lot of other crap
in the air um i was thinking about like
a cool technology thing
would be it's kind of hard to breathe
with one of these on so you can put it
on you guys can barely even hear me
i don't want any reminders i don't want
any virtue signaling
um so
yeah what i'd like to see is a mask that
has uh it's battery powered
and it makes it easier for me to breathe
right like they could constantly
circulate the air through these filters
um there's also ones that have the eye
thing if you really want to be if you
really want to be protected against some
stuff
um you're not gonna get air yeah so
that's what i'm saying like if you put
like a battery powered little uh
little like like fan on this thing i
think it would be awesome
my iq is over nine thousand bro
over nine thousand got nine thousand iqs
ah so yeah what we were looking at we
haven't gotten to the truth of uh
hydroxychloroquine um so
hydroxychloroquine alone
i wouldn't expect to do anything we're
looking for large
randomized studies on hydroxychloroquine
plus zinc
things have been all over the place and
i think one of the explanations for that
is some of them are using zinc and some
of them aren't using zinc
disturb the flow of air
why do you think that matters right
here's the other thing about social
distancing too
you know it's all great if you're
actually staying six feet apart but
let's say you're like in a line right
you breathe out particles are suspended
in the air
next person walks takes up your air
breathes in the particles gets the virus
right
so oh no it stopped the air from going
further away from you great it created
an even bigger cloud that the next
person's going to walk into like it's
it's
if you're not blocking the particles you
aren't doing
right where are the particles ending up
it's not it doesn't it doesn't kill
viruses
right there's always a question of where
the particles are ending up if you can't
answer that question very clearly
your mask does nothing um so to answer
the question for this thing
the particles end up inside these
filters which you can then replace
um you know i can i can pull this thing
apart
uh it's like too sure how to pull it
um but yeah so this for example
would be chock full of coronavirus uh
i'm showing it to the microphone not to
the camera
over 9000 is a joke from dragon ball z
um oh how about the psychological effect
i hate these things yeah what about the
psychological effect between behind
crosses
to remind everybody that god is up there
watching
right it turns out that people wearing
crosses commit 30 percent less murders
so we've made it mandatory for everybody
to wear crosses so they have a
psychological reminder that god is
watching them
all right we're done with those rants um
quick moment to give a shout out
to uh slate star codex
and uh you know they're dicks the new
york times said they're gonna dox him
and they're gonna get her post his his
stuff on the internet
um you know super dick uh and he deleted
his blog
which you know what honestly i don't
blame him um and i i think that this is
a concern
uh in general a lot with the kind of the
the kind of toxic atmosphere i know the
word canceled culture comes around a lot
what you're gonna get is you're just
gonna get a lot of very smart people
you know good people who just opt out
and say i'm not playing
you know this game sucks i'm not playing
okay no results posted oh the results
get posted here too
uh all right i know you guys posted them
before can we post them again
we got we got good start studies on
hydroxychloroquine plus zinc
um if there's any effect here it's what
i'd expect to s where i'd expect to see
it
i think the azithromycin does nothing
[Music]
no results posted all right we'll post
this one to keep an eye on
yo my sound is very low still very low
low sound no i'm pretty close to the max
db i can go a little louder on it i will
go a little louder oh
the other thing that we should listen to
is i think the best song
to come out of this
is hopson's coved mansion
you think the song is political
because you made fun of tick-tock and
only fans was that is that political
i don't know about that man
kumbaya was pretty good too yeah absent
hops and winning coronavirus
no the song is not political and if you
think that's like like this got a
twisted like
like you know does 5g cause coronavirus
no is it funny to say that it does yes
what the is wrong with people
that's that's a good question
that is a good question all right um
ja rule is watching naked and afraid
that's what cha
rule has to see what's not going to
break that's what that's that's ja
rule's opinion um
so wait so there's the good study
there's the study from recovery trial
about
um without zinc uh seems
ineffective
i mean this is a press release do they
have the actual
study
uh and we'll add in just because they
did it and these studies seem super high
quality
wouldn't expect it
to work
don't think kobit has
a protease
drugs are protease inhibitors
um so my understanding from the research
i did before on hydroxychloroquine and
zinc
is zinc blocks rna-dependent rna
polymerase so in the presence of zinc
you don't get replication of the virus
the problem is the virus is replicating
in cells
which zinc can't get to but
hydroxychloroquine or chloroquine is a
zinc ionopore
uh i think i used this as a citation for
that
i'm meaning it allows zinc into the cell
so before
evidence doesn't look great for
hydroxychloroquine but it doesn't seem
like these studies uh
gave supplemental zinc now supplemental
zinc may have no effect there may be
enough zinc just
in the human body that this effect just
isn't strong but yeah what i really want
to see is studies is
large-scale randomized control studies
like recovery trial
where they um
they also include zinc i don't think the
azithromycin has anything to do with
anything
uh unless people think it's it's
secondary bacterial infection causing
problems but i haven't seen
evidence for that
[Music]
um zinc generally stimulates areas of
the immune system
i haven't seen evidence for this either
um
i still i still really like the
hypothesis that zinc blocks
ah here this one i think was on happy i
have a bunch of citations there
um
i wish i could find the studies on this
too because i i want to see maybe they
just gave zinc and didn't really discuss
it
so this could actually be the study that
i'm looking for
full details of the study protocol and
related materials are available here
here we go study protocol
props to the uk this is all looks very
nice
removal of hydroxychloroquine
what so they removed it in june i don't
get it
previous versions of the study protocol
why did they remove it i don't get it
um okay so they did not
they did not give zinc uh
in the study all right we got we got
some links
here you have some english about zinc i
don't know about doom and bloom.net if
it looks like a conspiracy theory okay
it looks kind of like a conspiracy
theory website you gotta watch so many
damn conspiracy theories out there now
you know
666 of yours um
supplemental zinc restores antibody
formation and cultures of aged lean
cells i have no idea how any of that
translates
yeah i don't trust survival medicine to
be honest
thank you for subscribing okay uh in
vitro
i think is this the one i looked at i
really don't want in vitro studies i
want
i want the big controlled study i mean
these aren't weird things to take
right like honestly if i got
if i was on my coronavirus death bed
here's here's here would be my advice
right now
um i mean i want to see i wouldn't take
hydroxychloroquine and zinc right now
uh long qt lots of weird stuff i would
take
from that severe if i was on
supplemental oxygen and then if they
were going to put me on a ventilator
i'd take dexamethasone um
is this virus mutating like the flu
uh what was that slight star codex link
i don't have it anymore
all right we're gonna try some removing
subscriber only but guys if i see any
political
bill gates conspiracy theory you
know
we're going back to uh we're going back
to
subscribers only
um now i'm asking one question do we
have a large scale study
on uh
well so yeah you drugs binding
is gonna have nothing to do with uh
hydroxychloroquine's efficiency
okay let's see what we got
oh pi rx welcome
what is pi rx it seems cool we'll add
this to resources this is interesting
i don't know where to put it and we'll
just put it there
is there a way to get the entire dna
sequence yeah the entire dna sequence is
in my repo
um whoops not that one
um be careful uh this link will give you
coronavirus
um
so coronaviruses mutate less than the
flu
coronavirus are the longest known rna
viruses
and they have some dna error checking
mechanism yeah so if you want my
favorite website to track mutations
around the world is neck strain
uh my internet glitched again no
no
why does my internet clutch
pretty cool to watch lots of skills
oh my god you're banned you just got
yourself banned
all right we're back
uh yeah so this is next strain is good
at tracking uh
the mutations around the world of the
virus
maybe they have
um and then they like show which ones
are mutating
but for some reason coronaviruses
uh yeah oh this is exactly oh i have
seen this before i should have linked to
this
binary scores the existing hiv
inhibitors are around minus 10 to minus
and minus 13 for ramdesamir
uh who wants to talk about that oh my
god bill gates
yeah generative rnn model with
techniques and principles i was a do you
want to hmm
oh yeah next strain is a nice way to to
look for that
all right oh 600 oh results available at
the end of the month i think that's the
one i already have
this is another yeah
i looked at that one i'm excited about
that
um that's true i was ready to ban until
i saw the badges if you have
if you're a subscriber you have more
leeway in what you can say because
you're a better person because you have
a star next to your name
if you don't have a star next to your
name you're a worse person and you'll be
more harshly judged
um yeah no results of this yet what can
i
let's try searching on
clinicaltrials.gov
completed
like none of these have zinc
this one's hydroxychloroquine with the
zithromycin
i don't understand i'm clicked completed
all this websites
week week government people made bad
website
now it's cool that this exists though i
won't handle the government people too
much the word zinc doesn't appear once
here
um yeah binding score i i agree i don't
think that's that's
the fact that rim desevere also has
reasons we would expect it to work from
like a
um it's a conspiracy
you are banned we have zero dumb
conspiracy tolerance here
if you have smart conspiracy theories
we're always open to smart conspiracy
theories but like conspiracy theories
is mad dumb and they're banned there is
no hope with corona
uh not trying to do armchair science i'm
not trying to i'm not saying i'm doing
science right
now we're just doing information
gathering
why am i looking for zinc um because
zinc
so the belief is that hydroxychloroquine
itself does nothing against coronavirus
this is my like working hypothesis on
this and it may be wrong
but what i'd like to see is a big
randomly controlled study on
hydroxychloroquine plus zinc
these are things that are known to be
safe in the human population i see no
reason why they would
interact because again you know all
these things guys i'm not a doctor
the only thing i can tell you is that i
do promise you
without a doubt that this mask is way
more effective than a face diaper that's
the only thing i'll say without a doubt
and if that turns out to be wrong
you know then i'm wrong about everything
but um
slave star codex clarified his mass
position on part three
of the post let's see what we have
uh
i must have read this because this i
showed off that parachute study it's
great
yeah again i i agree with what he says
here
i agree with the rationality i don't
necessarily agree with the conclusion
um i think that the odds of them being
effective is
at least cloth masks masks that have
visible holes in them
is way lower than 80 and i think there
is a cost
um i think there's a costs coming from
one scientific and one non-scientific
factor and the scientific factor is
um i think you show that like people
wearing helmets on bikes hit their head
way more than people who don't
uh or what what is the there's like a
classic one where the effect is really
strong
where people think they are wearing a
form of protection and then they take
more risks that they otherwise wouldn't
take
um if for example people who got
vasectomies have a higher std rate
uh for obvious reasons um
the
uh oh look i'm not look i'm not giving
you any advice
you know you there's none of this is
advice all i'm saying is
are you trying to go to the airport you
have to separate your head these two
ideas right
am i trying to prevent myself from
getting coronavirus
prevent myself from getting coronavirus
prevent the spread of coronavirus to
other people
or um am i trying to placate the
authorities right
i wore this mask to the airport to
placate the authorities right
if the authorities demanded that i wear
an actual diaper on the plane because
you know bathrooms are shut down
well i'd do the same thing right
i'm not gonna i'm not one of those guys
who's like gonna make a
a stand about it right like it's not
worth making a stand for but
what what what bothers me about it is
the promulgation of of untruths
um wayfair is a smart
nfl with their helmets yeah
um
on truth hurts more in the long run and
that's um i had a conversation with a
friend
and he said look uh even if masks aren't
effective
you know if there's some chance that
they are we should say that the science
supports them
and sure in the short term maybe this is
a win but in the long term what it does
is it erodes trust and science in
general
uh and you don't want to do that like
it's not it's not worth it
um you know it's clearly printed on the
outside of every pack of cloth masks you
buy
this mask does nothing to prevent
viruses
yeah why are they trying hydroxyl
chlorine without zinc to be honest i
have no idea
um no i don't know why doctor disrespect
got banned but i'm as curious as you
guys
um whatever it is twitch if i did it
please just tell me
please tell me i don't want to be i
don't want to be disrespected
disrespected um
all right we have a journal link here
what do we got
uh are there any alternatives i mean
stricter lockdowns will stricter
lockdowns will definitely bring down the
spread of a virus so my conclusion at
the end of all of this
was all the lockdowns are going to do is
shift when the virus spreads
i think the only way through this is
herd immunity i also think that herd
immunity is closer than a lot of people
think
because okay so they say to get hurt
immunity you need to have a sixty
percent of people or seventy percent of
people have had to have the virus
depending on the are not but this isn't
exactly true
all you need is 60 or 70 percent of
people to not be able to get the virus
if it turns out that there's a
pre-existing immunity in 50
of the population then only 10 or 20
percent of the population needs to get
the virus
right um our culture is very bad at
talking about acceptable death and
unacceptable death
so right now i think there's like 135
000 deaths from coronavirus in america
if we're talking that order of magnitude
particularly when most of the population
who gets it is very old
this all this stuff was insane um if
we're talking about potentially three
million deaths one percent of the
population then maybe it's not insane
and if you're talking about 30 million
deaths i think everybody in america
would support martial law in the
military marching in the street
where does the 50 immunity come from so
my theory about this and if someone like
if there's some reason this is wrong
uh i do back so the data that i have is
that everywhere coronavirus has like
ripped through the population
right you can look at cruise ships you
can look at like some factories
i think the navy had a bunch of these
you see about 35 to 50 percent of people
become infected with the virus
now why did the other 50 not become
infected
i think the theory that it's because
they weren't exposed seems
rather low um i think it has more to do
with
well they have a pre-existing immunity
or some kind of uh
not talking about doc disrespecting here
though that's that's over
um
no i'm not i mean so here's here's an
interesting
i'm not i have my other my other piece
of evidence for this this this hurt
immunity is like
does new york city have heard immunity
right
um so the lockdowns the lockdowns are
are i'm in new york right now
i was just in california and i would say
that the lockdowns in new york and
california right now are at a very
similar level
you can eat outside you have to wear
masks in both places you can take masks
off when you're seated
number of people in the street seems
very similar yet new york looks like
this
and california looks like this um
so one potential explanation for that is
around here new york got pretty close to
herd immunity
it spread through most of the population
that could get coronavirus and now
you're just getting the tail end down
here
um let's see the study let's see the
study about about uh
how long does immunity last that's an
interesting question
um yeah it may require zinc additives no
like when did this come out they
should have just watched my stream
if they'd watched my stream they would
have known this
yeah chloroquine can induce the uptake
of zinc in the side of the cell which is
capable of inhibiting
rna are a rna dependent rna polymerase
this is what i
said on my last stream if only they'd
watched it they could have not done all
these stupid studies
uh here's an interesting finished study
about how
face masks have no uh impact is this a
real study or is this a conspiracy
theory website
because unfortunately i've seen so many
conspiracy theories both ways this is a
news website this is not well
let's see if it links to a real study
um the full report is available on the
ministry website in finnish well
oh sorry guys i'm not i'm not uh up to
date on my finish
finland does seem like a place in
general finland sweden
i think by the way of all the countries
on coronavirus i think iceland
uh did iceland did incredibly well you
don't go to iceland now you take a test
at the border
um
uh that is finnish official government
media well again
governments have their own perverse
incentives for doing anything
though i do feel that nordic countries
generally are more backed by science
uh uh yeah
i think i think iceland did the best um
they had this beautiful tracker website
from like day one and now you can go to
iceland you just take a test at the
border uh it helps a lot when your
country is only three hundred thousand
people
uh no masks in iceland yeah now to be
fair
saying no masks in iceland doesn't
necessarily say anything about the
ineffectiveness of masks
um it certainly speaks to the
effectiveness of iceland strategy which
is aggressive contract tracing
there's no doubt that effective con that
aggressive contact tracing works
it's a question of again if this comes
down to trust in government
um countries let's let's find a study on
this so i'm not just talking about my
ass
and maybe it doesn't confirm what i
believe but countries trust
in government
i love our world and data
yeah oh this is most people can be
trusted
um public trust in government u.s
here we go
these don't have do they have the nordic
countries
someone redirected you too many times
[Music]
i don't know they played music when i
went to it i kind of don't trust this
already
can we find like a real like trust in in
government
study
at least it's a pdf and won't play any
damn music
i don't have iceland
well i mean actually i i guess this is a
fine proxy for it too
uh a share of people agreeing with most
uh
most people can be trusted if you have a
high trust society something like
contact racing is going to work
um if you don't have a high trace high
trust society
uh yeah i mean you see sweden
very high trust i'm sure iceland is
similar but there's no data
pdf can play sound yeah maybe
um masks do indeed have effect
asians don't wash their hands as often
as europeans but the amount of cases
there
are much lower than the eu
what what what do you even say to that
what do you even say to a statement like
that except ban
oh this is study about duration of the
immunity yeah yeah we're going to look
into that let's see we got
meta meta-analysis on mass-producing
infections let's see what we have here
too
well this is this is real science let's
look at um
antibodies
and then we're going to look into
vaccines and i think that's going to be
the stream
uh longitudinal evaluation and decline
of antibody response
so my understanding of the immune system
is that there's two
uh there's igg and igm
and one of these is short term and one
of them lasts a long time
uh okay the igg igm and iga
what's iga
uh
igg takes time to form igm happens fast
i think the igm tests are the are they
like fingerprint blood tests for
coronavirus they can do
major types of antibody found in the
blood
that can enter tissues and fight
infection
i mean i think i looked this up for sars
and it didn't look
too bad for antibody
methods i just
let's say
okay this is decent uh
[Music]
wait is that axis not
oh yeah good yeah okay so this is this
is showing antibiotic concentration over
time
so it looks like igm and iga decline iug
declines a tiny bit
i mean i have seen this for colds as
well
where oh let's see here's the meta study
on face masks
well i mean just to read the conclusion
here uh transition to viruses was lower
with physical distancing of one meter or
more compared with distance less than
one meter so they found that with
moderate certainty um
protection was increased his distance
was lengthened
moderate certainty face masks could
result in a large reduction risk of
infection
low certainty with stronger
associations with n95 low certainty
my understanding is n95 masks are
similar to this mask also
in that they do not um they only filter
the intake air they do not filter the uh
the exhalation air
uh yeah no what is this north korea nice
censorship buddy
uh no it's actually it's it's it's worse
than north korea
because uh you see i'm sure that in
north korea
they make some word to justify the
regime but here we don't justify the
regime
here i'm dictator and i'm dictator
because i said so you know
you used to have divine right divine
right is you know why is the king of
france king of france
because god said so it's called divine
right right and then democracy comes
along and we replace this with the will
of the people
and the will of the people is because
the people said so look we voted in free
and fair elections
and now we have my twitch stream where
we have the i say so and i'm just
dictator and if i don't like we have to
say you're banned
and that's just how it works um
that's a significant change in uh
yeah this doesn't seem to show
this is not this is not a strong
i mean you know you can read there's
some like scammy studies on
hydrochloroquine alone because that was
that was
politicized for stupid reasons and like
you just read the study and you're like
this isn't science
um i heard south korea had good software
again high trust society
oh no no internets come back
all right all right all right coming
back
we back you back boys
2fps
seems okay um wouldn't masks be better
than nothing so
don't buy into this because you can make
the same argument for be
be aware of any argument that you can
make for wearing a cross around your
neck
right can you make the same argument
well a cross isn't going to kill people
north korea has better internet than
this yeah i don't know
uh i don't know why it's bad all right
um antibody so this doesn't look super
strong to me
in saying that there's just studies that
show
reinfection reinfection
covered
um i worry about national
review
this is at least a clinic
protective immunity is short lasting
again i'm less interested in studies
that show the decline of antibodies and
how they're measured because we don't
know what rate of antibodies is required
for immunity
what i'm interested in is showing
four seasonal human coronaviruses we
monitor healthy subjects
ah this is interesting
i wonder how they got this data
there's a bit of concern also about bias
and how this was collected
because have you ever i mean i'm sure
i've had plenty of coronaviruses in my
life i don't know how i've uh
been tested for it
i've never been tested for cold i mean
these type of sample collections are
difficult to obtain see this but this is
what i'm interested in so this seems
like at least a good way to
only increase after successful infection
also rise
with asymptomatic infection and do not
increase after unsuccessful viral
challenge
yeah serology-based reinfection dynamics
this is this is this is
this is good this is how i do this
they have like measles here as a control
measles is one that once you get it once
you don't get it again right
full change od absorbance relative to
previous visit i don't really follow
that
oh this is cute though they they can
detect reinfection by seeing a
re-expression of the antibodies but
no i mean that's not exactly right
because
all right it looks like things have been
junk
uh masks for all dot co
yeah you know
this isn't science this is politics
take action to save lives
yeah i'm interested in taking action to
save lives but i'm interested in what
action if you're using propaganda to
market to me
it's probably because the truth isn't on
your side
wait it's unlikely that a meta study on
wearing crosses would return even a low
certainty or reducing infection
i promise you if that study was carried
out by the catholic church
it definitely would considering the fact
that it's not double blind
you know and there's there's some
incentive on behalf of those researchers
right
yeah but again it doesn't matter you see
i'm just here i'm just here saying stuff
on a twitch stream right i'm not trying
i'm not trying to influence anybody
politically i'm just trying to find the
truth right
um and in general there's a kind of
um denialism right
denialism science denialism
whenever something's associated with
denialism
i always wonder like why right
why do they feel this need to brand
there's no
there's no math denialists out there
right there's no sun denialists
every time there have ever been
denialists of something you always like
wonder what the actual truth is
right where where where we know the
earth is the center of the universe
we're heliocentric denialists
well you know turns out the heliocentric
denialists for right
um the
the psychology of flat earthers is
somewhat interesting
um i think a large number of them are
trolls and a large number of them
are the kind of people who are very fed
up with like
you know being told things by sneering
smug experts
so it's kind of like funny it's like you
know you think you you think you're
going to convince me about about climate
change bro i don't even believe the
earth is
is round um and it's it's kind of a
like what it should be viewed as a
challenge
to well you have a choice now
you can either like take this person and
completely exclude them from the
conversation
which i think is a decent approach or
the other approach is like
please speak in scientific terms don't
make face masks for
all dot co and say things like take
action to save lives right
because when you have that you just you
just i don't know like i personally
i feel that kind of impulse i feel the
kind of impulse to be like
why are you using this cringe-worthy
language right
um the other thing about about flat
earthers my friend told me this story
about
her brother and our brother's a flat
earther
and he's the kind of person who didn't
do well in his life
he stayed in his hometown he doesn't
really have a job his friends moved on
he didn't really go to college
and you kind of have two hypothesis now
right you can be like well this has
something to do with me
and i didn't do well because of bad
decisions i made
or you can blame the world or you can
say the whole world conspired against me
look they won't even tell me the truth
about the earth being round
and like it's a psychologically
protective mechanism
for some people and it's just you know
again what
what can you do to that i think with
that kind of person you just have to
they're so deluded
that you just kind of have to exclude
them from from from civil discourse and
uh
you know hope that they get their
together and if they don't you know we
all make choices in life right
he's not a paranoid schizophrenic no
it's about fundamentally
things didn't go his way does he blame
himself or does he blame the world
the first step to moving forward is
blaming yourself um
so how do i know masks for all is about
politics and we can we can look at this
right
so let's let's let's um let's just look
at the outline of this website and i can
tell you why right away i know that it's
political
right so first off look at this
featured in right now some people still
think that these are news organizations
but i don't think they are i think
they're propaganda outlets right
i mean i think i think that most most
liberal people
would accept that fox news is a
propaganda outlet right
um and most conservative people would
accept that
cnn and abc are propaganda outlets but
the truth is they're all propaganda
outlets
um the way that this language is written
right is like and again i'm not saying
that
like it is it is political i think that
even even uh jeremy would agree with
this right in saying that this website
is a political statement not a
scientific statement right
learn about the benefits of masks right
and again it's the same kind of politics
when a company wants to sell you
their product right um learn about the
benefits of
bike helmets right i just saw a person
ride by on a bike with a helmet that's
why i thought of that
um but then also like when you have
language like this like
take action to save lives this isn't the
language of science this is the language
of
politics and propaganda right if
everybody
wears a cloth mask we're protecting each
other a highly politicized figure in the
united states
right look at this
76 percent of americans want masks to be
required
in business right so let's replace all
the things let's replace
all the masks here with gold crosses
right
and notice how everything still works
this entire this entire website
can is this is this easy for me to go
and replace things
um
uh gold crosses uh can help the spread
of of coronavirus
uh right here um
learn about the benefits of crosses
take action to save lives right
it's the same crosses for all like i can
i can replace
all of this the first statement that
they make about cloth masks is
76 percent of americans want masks to be
required in business that's not only a
political statement that's a democratic
statement
right that's believing in democratic
politics
um 86 percent of the world population
lives in places that have a nationwide
or statewide requirement of masks
none of this stuff says anything to do
with
prominent academic leaders have signed a
letter okay
now here we get down to here we get down
to many scientific studies so let's see
what we find right
now remember again this suffers
massively
from the uh the global warming problem
which is
look do i know if global warming is real
or not i've given my opinion on it
before i think that
the rise in carbon dioxide is certainly
real
um and there's certainly some negative
effects because of that and the rise of
carbon dioxide is certainly man-made
like you can find this very clearly with
evidence
um but like you know some of the claims
it's it's you're gonna see a lot more
papers arguing
one side of it than the other side of it
do you think masks for all
would post a neutral scientific paper
showing that masks really aren't that
effective
do you think do you think that they're
do you think they are dispassionate
investigators of this
right um now to be fair you know to
fully disclose biases i generally have a
bias on the side against this
on the side against like
you'll propagandize for that side well
you know i'm a contrarian i'll
propagandize for the other side right
um but yeah i mean when your first three
facts
talk about are appeals to authority
appeals to democracy
and appeals to government's correctness
that's junk
right they wouldn't cite opposing
studies i would if somebody shows me a
real study which shows the effectiveness
of masks
i promise you i will post it on here
right now i will read it
and i'll be like damn okay i was wrong
um but yeah and i'll give you know just
pre-registration i'll tell you what i
want the study to be i'd like this study
to be
a it can't be double blind but at least
uh controlled and randomized so we have
like
she's got to do a big study probably
like 10 000 volunteers in a city
sign up we randomized half of them to
wear masks half of them to not wear
masks
and then we look at the coronavirus
infection rates and the mask squares
versus the non-mask squares
right now unfortunately it's not double
blind um
so you might say that the people wear
masks take less risks because they know
they're in the mass group
or you might say the people with masks
take more risks
because they feel like they're protected
because they're wearing a mask
but either way if somebody posts that
study
i believe it right but again fast ai i
mean he's making political statements
about masks
didn't they show me many papers well
again i want to see that paper
i don't want to see papers that talk
about uh the
spewing of particles right because it's
not a question about particles it's a
question about whether you're likely to
get infected
um
the reason that the reason that i care
and the reason that i've taken some time
to
to rally against it is because it's
you know it's mandated right a lot of
the stores now have signs
masks required to enter right and like i
feel similarly if they said cross is
required to enter right
you're pushing your religion on me don't
do that
[Applause]
um
i'm definitely not anti-science uh
although i believe so i mean i'm not
even sure what it would mean to be
anti-science right
i i believe fundamentally like i want to
live forever all right uh
living forever is a very difficult
technical challenge it's going to
require a lot of work
to figure out exactly how to do this
right and propaganda
is is is the enemy right like
if if with propaganda you can end up in
holes and believing dumb for for a
long time
um and then what i worry even more about
is the collapse of the ability to find
real truth
um no and it's not it's not it's not
don't say it's like
push by the left people say oh yeah the
left is pushing the right is
pushing
they're both pushing it's all
right you want real truth go on med
archive
and be weary of language that sounds
either leftist or righteous
the test you propose is like letting
people eat poison and seeing how many
die how many survive to come to a
conclusion
i'm not saying we force anybody to do
this i would happily volunteer uh for
the study
right i think a lot of people would
i mean it's it's consensual people are
aware of the risks
i think that a study with poison like
that is fine if people really don't
believe that
again as long as everybody's consenting
and understands they may end up in
either one of the randomized groups
um yeah well the aerosol studies aren't
what i'm looking for
right uh the the problem with
the you know you can uh
what i'm looking for is a study on
infection rates
um stopped by typical use of uh
of surgical masks in public right why
wouldn't they allow such studies
that's ridiculous again
it's volunteers who fully understand the
risks of being in
both groups i believe that this does
nothing
um what prayer is good for
the evidence for it
i i don't trust national review to be a
dispassionate
just just just judging from the title i
think it's right-wing propaganda
um if you don't want confusion in your
chat use painting or
notepad instead of fully verbalizing
your points on stream
cross's face maths are a tool again
you know um
what do we got here
the book of y the new sign so judea
pearl wrote i read your today pearls
back in the day a book on causality
um do we need to go do we need to get do
we need to go to uh
he's be he's big on causality and and i
should revisit these ideas now that i
know like the stuff i know about uh
machine learning and like what is the
actual definition of causality
ah yeah defining what event truly causes
i mean it's certainly correlated light
switches being flipped upward and
light's going on
is certainly correlated but how can we
truly say that the light switch causes
it it's not just correlated
uh it's a good question so no idea if
i'm very useful
it's hard to imagine anyone who's not
dealing with cause and effect
um so you can imagine you can't imagine
this this idea of
a counter factual to get a causality
which is you could imagine the world
splitting into two
one world where you know i i uh do the
intervention in one world where i don't
and then i check if the outcomes are
different and this is
usually viewed to mean
if you define it that way and you can
define that rigorously
that means causality that's just what we
use for the definition
is the study guide so remember what
we're looking for
i'm more interested if anyone finds a
hydroxychloroquine
no this is not a good study so do it
yourself figure out why that's not a
good study
[Music]
not looking for simulations i'm looking
for
the study which we could very clearly do
right it's not an unethical study it's
really not
um
yeah causality is a fun thing to think
about
but i mean i remember reading his books
and i remember like
i remember coming away kind of with the
contrarian opinion that like
correlation is causation
it's clearly not this is counter factual
but like
or maybe there is no way to learn this
idea of
true causation outside of correlation uh
you could imagine that there is a deity
in the sky who watches you flipping
light switches and then turns the light
on and it's the deity that actually does
it and not like the switch
um but then at that point what kind of
study do i want
what i'm looking for is a large
randomized controlled study of
hydroxychloroquine
plus zinc there's one registered on
clinical trials
but it doesn't have results mostly yet
wow
let's see what the exercises are
as i re-read genesis for the hundredth
time i noticed a nuance that
i don't know uh so where are we popping
off the stack
coronavirus immunity is is short-lasted
it's short-lasting
um what percent of people get a cold
each year
so let's look quickly let's look um
huh
really one to three times
i mean one thing that'll be cool that if
we end up getting
out of this if we get a vaccine
i'm not bullish on a vaccine for a bunch
of reasons but if we do
i wonder if these vaccines will work on
colds too
i hate getting colds
um all right we're done we're done we're
done oh here we go
uh we're done we're done talking about
masks for now um
the study that would convince me is a
it's it's totally not unethical to do
uh okay here we go
do we have no results posted
here's another study that we're waiting
for the results on when are we supposed
to get them
september 2021 we're all going to be
dead by then
um
is this the study i wanted
huh okay
[Music]
the efficacy of cloth masks versus
yeah this this this matches with what i
would believe which is what i stated
which is what i
i stated cloth mask does nothing this
maybe something but unlikely this
protects you from front of eyes
um so this is this is good these are the
kind of studies that i'm looking for
well let's not let's not quickly uh
let's not jump too quickly to
conclusions but
it was done in a lot of places um was it
randomized
or was it the people who chose to wear
cloth masks
um this study is the first rct of cloth
masks and the results caution against
the youth of cloth
mouth cloth masks moisture retention
reuse of cloth mask and poor filtration
may result in increased risk of
infection so our first legitimate
looking mask study and what do we find
oh it's old too
um randomized oh they have a control
group too
your control group didn't wear masks
standard practice which may or may not
include mask use okay
oh irb deemed it unethical to ask
participants to not wear a mask
okay
so i questioned the control group but
i mean just looking at just looking at
those numbers nothing else
uh medical masks and nothing are about
the same and cloth masks
seem detrimental
[Music]
oh here they have compliance too oh cool
they do have the noise this is a good
study
good study
[Music]
uh i did i didn't like get something
obviously wrong right i think the
control group was slightly smaller
this is the number of people who got
sick um we
i don't like that they don't post this
should be a percentage
there shouldn't be a number if the
groups are different sizes unless the
groups are the same size
yeah the control group is slightly
smaller um
the control group is slightly smaller
medical mass got slightly more
let's just like like let's just get the
percent here
so the medical mask arm
um
all right so we have uh then
equals medical mask uh cloth mask
and control
then the number of people who got a
detectable virus
was medical maths cloth masks control
uh x over y or x comma y
and zip done
and let's actually also multiply that by
100 so we can get percent
so this is the oh i'm in python 2.
oh i'm in python 2. okay
so wearing medical masks 3.2
of people got infected wearing cloth
masks 5.4
and wearing well control means about
half the mask used to the others we got
3.9
so evidence is you know and we can do
how do i do a p-value
p-value analysis we'll do real science
right
people only claim cloth masks protect
other people from you right the goal
posts move
big holes man big holes
but i like this look we found a real
study
real science no political propaganda
p value analysis javascript i want like
an online like
here we go
no no no i want like a good here we go
no this isn't what i want either
there should be like i forget how to do
this like so
is it is it statistically significant
with a population size
can we show statistical significance
um that that can we show first off that
well medical mask is high is is lower
rate than control
so is this a statistically significant
amount given that denominator
and then cloth masks got more infection
can we show that this is this
statistically significant
there's like ways to do this
but i don't know it off the top of my
head i should
all right we will now calculate the z
score
okay population mean
sample mean
calculate a z-score for any
raw value of x so what are how do i do
this
who knows how to do this
again you want to show me protecting
other people post
the the the the rule for evidence
oh okay wait do we have do we have a
good do we have results on this one do
we have an actual good trial on zinc
plus hydrochloroquinolone
um no oh sorry i closed twitch
this is just kind of embarrassing
can we post that study again that one
looked good
sorry i opened that in the wrong
browser alright we got it
um does zinc supplementation enhance the
clinical effectiveness so let's take a
look and see if there's a good study or
not
great great hypothesis oh we proposed to
amend but i don't think they actually
did the study
uh no but yet you claim
oh estimated by 31st of july okay use
r and use p norm to get the cumulative
distribution
i don't know r
begin bot welcome r p norm
distribution function all right
god
i've seen this stuff before i'm just not
sure
what this stuff means i mean the
question i'm asking like is
is it statistically significant can we
say with statistical significance that
cloth masks make you more likely to
catch a virus than wearing no mask at
all
that'd be that'd be some if we could
prove that we're doing science boys
we're doing science i don't know why
it's highlighted with
cannot assume normality especially with
the crucial wallace tests np
dot cumulative right
one nominal variable and one ranked
variable damn i don't know any
statistics
um
wait why can't we assume that it's it's
it's randomly distributed why can't we
assume that it's a normal distribution
what's the issue with which study for
what
because this isn't testing this is
testing
hypothetical things that may correlate
with the spread of a virus
right i don't want to hear about oh it
like it it
changes the particle distribution of
this
you'd also then have to show that
changing the particle distribution
affects the virus the study i want to
see looks like this
right you have a medical math group
a medical mass group a cloth mass group
and a control group
hopefully there's no other difference
between those three groups now be aware
that people know which mask they're
wearing so
it's not truly blinded but like i don't
see a better way to do this study
show me this and then show me how many
of them got infected
right if you and then and then do the
statistical analysis
and then you can show if masks reduce
the spread of coronavirus or not it's a
simple study to do and it's really not
unethical
even if you just did a control study
where you did the same thing here if
they say
forcing people to wear masks you can't
do just do
um you know one group of people can do
whatever they want
and the other group of people should
comply and then we can measure it we
could show
effectively what this graph is um
and then you know we can see what
percent of people get viruses we can
check for all different kinds of viruses
too not just coronavirus
um and figure out what masks are
effective
uh couldn't the masks all look the same
yeah i mean ideally the control group is
a mask that looks the same but actually
changes nothing
read the bottom of this from the world
health organization
again a lot of questions about the world
at the bottom of this
this isn't this is this is political
this isn't it doesn't matter what it
says
i think the world health organization
actually has uh
an opinion that that that widespread
mass use doesn't do anything but like
either way
again it's it's political propaganda so
i can't trust them either way
what i do trust is this study
a cluster randomized trial of cloth
masks compared with medical masks do it
in healthcare workers do it in the
general population
it says cloth masks are not recommended
under any circumstance
like again because the world health
organization says something
you do have to um what's the the classic
this is a less wrong
um idiot says the sun out
says the sun is out
what's uh here we go
yeah uh
your reverse stupidity is not
intelligence
this is robert percy because that's that
in the art of motorcycle maintenance guy
i liked that book when i was younger
yeah
um the world's greatest fool may say the
sun is shining
but that doesn't make it dark out
reverse stupidity is not intelligence
um are healthcare workers really a good
representation
ah
the masks masquerade article from to lab
again i agree
let's let's look quickly at what he says
but again regardless
whether he agrees or doesn't and i don't
know the masked masquerade seems like he
agrees with me
but again that's not evidence right it's
not evidence either way
ah he's pro man again god pro mask and
and and
this is this is political
this is it oh we got to study
face mask use in the control of
respiratory
okay it was done a while ago let's see
what we got
um we studied a
randomized comparing surgical masks and
no mask
adherence to mask use
significantly reduce the risk this is
better
all right let's see what we got um
so it's a smaller study
all right let's let's let's post let's
let's add a we'll add a mask section to
this
guys you know you might you might you
might change my mind by the end of this
legit change my mind not like louder
with crowder
um
i think i mean i'm put it this way if i
had to assign
uh confidence values to these things i
am 90
confidence on the uselessness of cloth
masks
i'm 60 percent confident i'm confident
on the uselessness of uh surgical masks
and i'm one percent confident on the
uselessness
of real uh respirators
all right let's see the study
face mask use and control of respiratory
virus transmission in households
so i would guess that i mean first let's
see if the viruses
are uh
so this is talking about rhino i think
most people got rhinoviruses
from this study rhinoviruses are cold
let's just quickly look them up because
i mentioned that again
uh talking about you know 20 percent of
colds are caused by coronaviruses and i
just repeat that
um is there any reason to think that a
rhinovirus would be a smaller or larger
particle
probably not
yeah so most of the viruses we're gonna
know what is this by the way
how should i be afraid of this
another cold virus interesting
um
286 exposed adults from 143 households
had been exposed to a child with
clinical respiratory illness were
recruited
we found that adherence to mask use
significantly reduced the risk but less
than
50 percent of participants wore masks
most of the time
we concluded that household use of face
masks is associated with low adherence
and is ineffective for controlling
okay i mean that's that's that's a
different question
um surgical masks
p2 masks what's a p2 mask
oh p2s or n95s okay
oh yeah my opinion on n95 so i gave a
yeah i gave a one percent chance and i
would say
i would give a 10 chance to n95s being
useless
um meaning i would give a 90 chance to
n95s being useful
uh let's say let's say let's say 70 30
let's say 30
chance that these are useful and let's
say a 10
chance now you know what we'll give low
we'll give lower i'm i'm as unconfident
in cloth masks
as i am confident and surgical now in in
in in p100 respirators
um okay control
surgical p2
uh seems sufficiently randomized
um adherence wasn't great
people complained about it but here we
go here's here's the real study
control group wait
control group has zero
confirmed infections surgical masks
has six and p2 masks has eight
um what do they claim this shows
am i reading this wrong
no this isn't the hanoi study this is uh
this is
this is a study that claimed to show
that it was effective
yet i see the opposite
i don't i don't know what i'm doing
wrong
they do show that a confounding factor
in the study is that they had low
compliance
i'm not trying by the way i'm not trying
to show that people with masks are more
likely to get the virus though the via
the hanoi study does seem
i don't know this was referred to as the
hanoi study i didn't realize this was
like a big thing
like people have like names for the
studies and stuff
the control group probably stayed inside
well so
again um this is about households right
this is about
kids who had some sickness and whether
you should wear a mask if your kid gets
sick
so staying inside right again
i really am open to
to to to to evidence and to a study
i've been linked to two things that i
thought were decent studies
and then like i'm also open to being
told that i'm reading these studies
wrong
but what i'm seeing here is that
more people again okay so here the here
the mask group
is uh is twice as large as the non-mask
group
but i don't know what the parenthesis
mean but it's still
two versus seven and here
check this out we got another one i see
the word policy in that name
i'm concerned
policy
well to see political propaganda got the
word policy in it again
whether it agrees with me or doesn't
agree with me
doesn't make a difference it's still
propaganda
this here is published in a journal and
this is from ncbi
this is what matters
i'm not 100 again i gave i gave a 10
chance that these things are in effect
[Music]
they might not be i don't know
studies that were done before the
outbreak are generally more likely to be
reliable too so both of these studies
this one comes from 2014 this one comes
from 2009.
they also gave a one percent chance that
they were ineffective sorry i revised it
for 10.
i mean i don't know 110. yeah i think
how do humans really think about this
kind of stuff um
no i would give i don't know there's
some chance that these don't block
particles at all let's let's look into
this quickly
um but no i mean again n95s are another
the ones that also include the eye
shield and stuff like there is
definitely a way to filter viruses out
of the air
everything that disagrees with your
opinion is propaganda no
no if that's what you take away from
that then that's more on level thinking
right that's that's that's more on level
thinking
um
what do we got what do we got here
because you're gonna you you
medical mask versus cotton mask
um done re wait no i don't know
uh
so let's take a look
objective of this study
okay i don't see the graph that i want i
told you guys before i looked at
anything what the graph i wanted is
i want this
i want this that's not what this is
this is
droplet levels i don't want anything
about droplet levels
i want a real control study that says
wearing masks nowhere in masks
i don't know what the political
incentive is i don't know how these
political people think i don't get why
the christians want you to wear crosses
or something that doesn't make sense to
me either none of it makes sense to me
this makes sense to me
all right all right all right all right
if you guys want to post about masks
i want more studies that look like these
two
looking for large
controlled studies
measuring
infection rate
no i need a report that has basically
like like yeah large controlled studies
measuring infection rate
with without compliance
wearing masks that's the evidence i'll
except
cloth masks aren't meant to filter out
by it doesn't matter right like it's
like
i would i would accept evidence of
crosses that did this study
if they did a large controlled study
where half the people wore
crosses and half the people didn't wear
crosses and they showed a statistically
significant
uh reduction from wearing across
and it was randomized and it was like
really as blind as you could make it and
you didn't have like obvious other
confounding factors
i'd go around wearing a cross man
yeah well p value statistically
unfortunately
i don't know um
[Music]
whoa a study of hydroxychloroquinoline
and zinc and 42 000 people
all right i like what we're going so far
to youtube
up all right all right all right
what do we got here
um respiratory
infection rave personnel
supplemented by use of masks and goggles
all right let's see what we find here
uh a few good things about this study
it's old
um unfortunately i can't buy it so i'm
gonna leak you guys uh
you guys don't know about the sci hub
bro you got to know about the cy hub
let's see who we got
okay um
mask goggles no mask goggles control
all right i'm not exactly following what
happened here did they
well first off the thing that i did
before was let's see if these viruses
are similar to coronavirus let's see if
we would expect
yeah i think we'd expect similar stuff
it's another cold
um
number of workers with rsv illness
versus percent exposed
number of workers with clinical
respiratory
okay so this seems to show that
if you don't wear anything you're fine
if you wear masks and goggles you might
get it
and if you don't wear a mask but you do
wear goggles you're
[Music]
wait is that is that am i reading this
wrong i think that's what it says
number of exposures seems to correlate
highly with
uh whether you get it
what's the conclusion
in healthcare workers using masks and
goggles
did not wear masks and goggles and the
other they did
using masks and goggles was no mask
goggles control
oh does this mean no goggles i guess
that assume that means no goggles
and what's the control group here i
guess the control group isn't
isn't uh okay all right this this seems
like it's it's it's evidence
let's quickly summarize here um
cloth masks bad
surgical
masks nothing um
this one
i was confused by what they ended up
stating
uh because of how this thing looks
um
i'm just gonna write a note about how i
trust pre-covet studies more but that
shouldn't be how science works
i'm just going to say unclear low
adherence
and here
uh
not understanding what they mean here by
control group
but it certainly looks statistically
significant between
mask goggles and no mask goggles
what kind of masks did they wear
and what was the control group
number of contacts definitely seems
correlated that seems very intuitively
true
[Music]
paul and douglas found that additional
use of mass and gowns
did not result in
measurable benefits we demonstrated the
infection of volunteers by the
installation of virus containing fluid
who wore masks and goggles who didn't
huh
they talk more about their protocol in
this
finally goggles are expensive
it's possible that the decrease in
infection in workers was not a primary
effect but a secondary effect
unclear
what did they mean by a mask are these
p95 masks or these cloth masks or these
medical masks
surgical masks i95 masks
hmm
masks plus goggles help
unclear of mask type
we got a randomized control group
what do we got
effectiveness of cloth mask so again all
right i'm a little more concerned
the thing that i liked about the other
three studies is they're all
pre-coronavirus so i trust them more
right as the result of the coronavirus
disease pandemic supplies of medical
masks and respirators are limited
globally
right notice how this paper doesn't use
any kind of language like that
nosoconomical infections with
respiratory signical virus are a
significant cause of mobility and
mortality and pediatric warts
they start with a word that most people
don't even know
[Music]
um
we can we can look into what these
studies were particularly if they were
older studies
or she say this is a randomized
controlled study
well it's the same people
this is the same this is the same people
only one randomized controlled trial has
been done to examine the efficacy of
cloth masks in healthcare settings and
the results do not favor the use of
cloth masks
is that their study oh it's their study
they're just citing themselves
but they are right
um yeah so i'm all for if you run
if i ran a store um i would have one of
two policies and i'd have to decide
i'd either have the uh no mask policy or
the
n95 masks n95 plus mask required for
entry
um here's another one for n95s again i'm
not sure what the result
is yeah look i'm not
i'm open to changing my mind
i wouldn't be looking into it if i
wasn't open to changing my mind that's
pretty stupid
um a cluster randomized clinical trial
departing fit tested all right all right
cool
[Music]
um
all right let's find let's see if we can
find that same chart
so they did they had three groups they
didn't have a control group they had
medical mask which i assumed surgical
mask n95 fit tested n95
not fit tested now let's find that that
same
that same thing i'm looking for that
looks like this
uh here we go now
um whether people used it or didn't use
it
uh intention to treat analysis
attack rates
okay so
here we go i don't know what cri
oh it's just a way of measuring the
the likelihood it's just another ili
this is less sensitive
okay so the results here
seem to show about a 2x reduction
from n95s versus medical masks
2x more effective than
[Music]
medical masks
yeah i i mean i would believe that right
that that that seems to
that seems to match with
what i stated uh let's just commit this
to github and make sure the
formatting looks okay
okay
so yeah n95 masks don't uh
do anything for anybody else but they
seem to lower your risk of infection
2x at least according to this study
which again studies that have that are
good studies
study arm
uh they talk about exactly how they uh
determined it
uh and then evidence for fit tested
versus non-fit tested
seems just roughly not really to matter
one study from 2009 comparing n95 to
surgical masks
what i'm really looking for is cloth
masks versus nothing
like that that's that's the point that
i'm looking to make here the thing that
i believe is that cloth masks are
completely ineffective
and all the mask requirements are stupid
um or if we want to be if we want to
actually reduce spread
let's mandate i-95 masks
um do we have the oh
i want the chart i want the chart
oh yes chart oh perfect
here we go chart surgical mask
n95 respirator
shows seemingly no effect
wait why does this have a p-value of
similar in those huh
meeting the criteria for non-inferiority
maybe yeah well
so that's i mean it's interesting how
you get a completely different result
with this study
surgical similar in effectiveness
they don't like have a secret control
group in here because i'd love to study
with the control group
what no no no we definitely definitely
don't talk about political
in here i don't want to hear no
dissipation studies
no dissipation studies and we got to go
subscriber only because you people
you know got into stupid fights we do
science bros we do science
all right we we're closing the mask
chapter
close the math chapter we got to move on
to vaccines this stream can't go on
forever
um i'm sticking with
zero evidence for anything good coming
out of people wearing
boxers on their face um
i'm sticking with face diapers probably
doing very little
uh you know again
it all seems to be i mean here's okay
i'll make i'll make i'll make one more
comment on the masks thing
like imagine we were evaluating
whether a uh whether a drug
should be used to treat coronavirus
right
like let's say the drug has some
potential side effect right
let's say there is some downside to
using the drug
i am quite confident that we would not
be using the drug
given the effectiveness studies i've
seen on masks right like these are not
effective and like i think the argument
that you can kind of make is is there a
negative side effect or is there not a
negative side effect
personally i think seeing those
restrictions on
uh on businesses especially when they're
government mandated
is a huge negative side effect right now
again
sometimes with a drug you're willing to
tolerate negative side effects
you can look at the drugs that treat
cancer drugs that your cancer have huge
negative side effects
but people still take them because
there's been many studies proving their
effectiveness
um so yeah uh
my conclusion on masks is uh they're a
scam
uh except for like real serious masks
maybe even gotta go all the way up to
p100s
if you're driving around in a tesla uh
you're not gonna get uh
tesla with the bio tesla bio
filter mode
hepa filter bio weapon defense mode
see what we got
[Music]
another personal mask anecdote
and i don't know actually i don't know
if this one would be better right
um i wore one of these to the casino in
san diego the casino smelled like smoke
with the mask it still smelled like
smoke
i wore one of these in the volcano and i
couldn't smell no sulfur until it
slipped off my face
um science man do not pay a lot for
boxer very
nice boxer very good cloth should i
should i
you know look i'm wearing i'm wearing a
mask
i'm wearing mask i wear a mask actually
this is pretty comfortable
wait this is seriously mad
comfortable this is what i'm wearing for
now on as a mask
i love this wait oh this is
brilliant
all right i was figuring out what to do
about like you know people like you
gotta wear masks
and i'm like oh i don't like masks mask
is uncomfortable but now
i found very comfortable calvin klein
mask oh yeah oh very nice
[Music]
this is just a pair of boxers yes
they're clean
they're definitely clean
boxer mask boys
okay
um no i actually have a saying at comma
which is you know there's not no
politics here because if you have a
place with no politics
uh you end up getting the worst kind of
politics
uh i say there's many politics
and they're all mine and you know it's
just it's just
you know whatever i believe because
welcome to my stream where i'm a
dictator
okay let's go back to vaccine is there a
vaccine
let's find out
see this is an example of the new york
times let's see this is good this is not
propaganda
for the most part let's let's see if
there's any propaganda words in here
researchers around the world are
developing more than 155 activities
against chronovirus and 23 vaccines are
in human trials
vaccines typically require years of
research but scientists are racing to
produce
a safe and effective
okay all right those are propaganda
words but otherwise we're pretty good
uh work began with the deciphering the
genome first vaccine safety trials and
humans started
in march some trials will fail okay
we may succeed in stimulating the immune
system to reduce i wonder do all
do all vaccines work like that
mcdonough plans phase 3 trials
it uses mrna to produce viral proteins
masks talk is over we're over masks guys
i have found my personal solution to the
mask which is
boxers on your face no more talking
about them
using mrna to produce viral proteins
then i assume
use mrna to produce
viral proteins
and then i assume your immune system
recognizes the viral proteins makes at
the body so on and so forth
self-amplifying okay so these all seem
to be okay
um dna vaccine
uh which here we'll just put um
we'll just move the stuff down from here
[Music]
so okay it looks like they're either all
they can't the new york times cannot
help themselves
they cannot help themselves
they they really sad
sad
yeah it's on github
viral vector vaccines
[Music]
modern
no
okay that use a virus to deliver
coronavirus genes into the cells to
promote
to provoke an immune response
so a few general questions that i have
about vaccines
um
which are like something that i always
ask in
in in in tech when someone comes to me
with an idea is why hasn't it been done
before
so there's no vaccines for other
coronaviruses as far as i know
i'm pretty confident in that so
why would there be one now
i mean like i would why is there not a
cold shot
okay protein-based vaccines viral vector
vaccines
and we can look into like what virus
they're potentially using
protein based
and whole virus vaccines which are the
typical
normal like
old vaccines
hmm whoa these are actually coming along
pretty fast
that's impressive
are any of these studies out yet
[Laughter]
okay okay i got him for a minute i i
gotta i got it for a minute
the wuhan institute of biological
products
is furthest along with the vaccine
nanoparticle-based vaccines
you have a link
an inactivated virus vaccine i wonder
what they're doing
no severe wow
what time
approval do we have any papers on these
does anyone have any links to papers
on the vaccines
ah well we learned about rsv from the
other thing um
all right well we'll add this as a
possibility
i don't know if efficacy so the standard
um in america for getting uh drugs
approved is different from the european
standard i don't know about other where
in the world but
in europe you just have to show that
something's not harmful you don't have
to show efficacy in america you have to
show efficacy
there's no point in trying to find that
all data is
biased and politically skewed that's not
exactly true
there's always a way to find truth
oh yes you still have to obviously show
that it's not harmful in the us
let's see what wikipedia says about it
is
the page good
um did not expect a vaccine to become
available
world health organization
big money telethon
um 19 human testing one
so this seems to be this seems to be the
one in phase three
[Music]
in europe you can try to approve a
lollipop i think you can
i think that works
oh i should i switch my filters out to
the medical filters
oh p100 oh see now this is gonna work oh
yeah this seems very effective
i put some of those in here we'll get
some effective
all right my internet's dying
[Music]
no internet come back internet
99.97 that's pretty good
rounds up to 100.
oh wow they really break it down here
non-replicating viral vector
i guess that gets it into cells
oh there's actually dna based vaccines
in human trials
wow this is cool okay this is a lot
further along than i thought
[Music]
um what's an adenovirus
right is that supposedly this one
is that sino farm is that one here
let's sign a farm not on here supposedly
the biggest
this is moderna
[Music]
flip it down a particle dispersion
containing
messenger rna so basically i think the
trick here is to get your body to make
the uh
encode the spike protein yeah yeah oh
this is cool
phase one open label dose ranging
clinical trial
is there any is there any evidence this
works
that seems terrible
i don't know if that's the same thing
and this might be one of those spaces
like self-driving cars where basically
everybody knows all the tricks but they
all like
refuse to tell anybody that they all
know the tricks
all right there's really no evidence the
only one here that seems to have any uh
oh yeah we're gonna look up what an
adenoviruses i don't think we looked it
up
common viruses that cause a whole set of
things
what is adenovirus and should i be
worried about it
i hate when they took danny davis you
have propaganda
when i find the secret to live forever
will i share it with the scopies hell no
all right so it's
my conclusion on vaccines is not anytime
soon especially if the immune response
isn't good
lipid nanoparticles so that's what what
this this uh the mrna ones are
this is mrna oh cool i'll see in the
papers
let's actually just link the pdf
mices they gave the mice as the
coronaviruses
pre-fusion stabilized all right so they
dig yeah
it seems like they're sticking the spike
protein
which we remember that from before
high
forget exactly what this was
yeah so the antibodies actually make it
worse
i remember reading about this a while
ago
self-amplifying rna that's cool
does it have rn how does it repeat
you
all right it seems like there's a lot
more to learn about self-amplifying rna
but my thoughts on viruses
uh my thoughts on vaccines are it's
still going to be a bad long time
oh interim results alright what do we
got
an rna vaccine let's read the study if
anyone wants to link studies we'll read
some studies
and they really got to do exposure
studies you know those are the real
studies
we're done looking at mask studies
unless you find exactly the one i'm
looking for now you know what
i almost want to do this study i
could fund this study
we're going to get
you need a lot of people because most
people don't get it
but in a place with a high infection
rate
i'd like to recruit like 10 000 people
and
have half of them wear cloth masks
always and half of them wear cloth masks
as little as they possibly can
and then we see how many people get
chronovirus
that's the study i want
so until i see that study uh
i'm bearish on uh yeah we're at we're
we're over mask stuff
um we looked at a bunch of studies
didn't find conclusive evidence anyway
and i think it comes down to whether you
think that the default should be masks
or the default should be no masks
and god you know that actually is a
political question so
it's all hopeless
can i glance at this in common testing
the efficacy of
homemade masks right again
i'm gonna pre i want to see that that
this i want to see this
i want to see this if it doesn't have
this
no no i don't want filtration no i want
i want this i want a graph that looks
like that
no not the dissipation hypothesis no the
dissipation hypothesis i just think is
wrong
um no what's political is whether you
believe let's say masks do nothing
right should people wear them or not
wear them
i mean i think you'd have people who
still say people should wear them so i
mean that's
at that point there's no science has
done its part right
um this is a general thing a general
thing about rationality
uh rationality can never
make policy decisions you cannot use
science to make policy decisions
in your personal life you cannot use
rationality
to determine what you should do right
like asking like what i should do with
my life
science can't answer that question
because it's not really a scientific
question
the only thing science can have the kind
of question science can answer is
questions that look like if we do x will
y
happen right
i mean there's definitely a downside i
don't like it right
there's no downside to wearing crosses
either and then any evidence you want to
give i already made this point
multiple times on this stream um but
yeah i mean there is no
if there's no downside or no upside
whether you wear it or not
you can't i mean science doesn't have an
opinion on that
right even if your goal is to reduce or
increase the spread of corona
even if your goal is like like withers
science can only answer the question
will widespread use of cloth masks
reduce the spread of coronavirus
right even if science answers that
question as no you know
right i think filtration studies aren't
related yet at all
with uh our masks i don't think uh
filtration studies answer that question
at all
the question will widespread use of
cloth masks reduce the spread of
coronifiers that's the question that
i've never seen a
definitive answer to
um the rna based
rbd binding what's rbd binding
what's rbd
receptor binding receptor binding domain
binding atm machine
no science can also it's not a
the interpretation can be done by
science as well right
so the measurement is a completely
separate thing the data gathering
science can interpret data
but science can only interpret data to
answer like like
questions about what will happen it's
predictive
it's not like generatives
even if the benefit is small the
short-term discomfort of wearing a mask
is worth it to get the whole pandemic
over with faster what if the benefit is
negative
what if cloth masks actually make more
people sick
right which is what this study shows
see that's that's a bad like like
again does your statement apply to gold
crosses as well
well if you want to study about how
would a cloth mask make someone sick you
can read the study
which is the only study of the of the
mask studies i looked at that talks
about cloth masks
you know honestly oh this has been a
theme of the comic youtubes as well
just recent recent stuff has just made
me feel so hopeless for humanity man
you know here we are we develop all of
this really nice stuff you know we
develop all of these beautiful
scientific machineries math that i can't
even begin to comprehend
and like you know we have we have
legitimate flat earthers
i mean those are that's an easy target
to rip on and it's fairly apolitical
um but there's a whole lot of political
ones you could rip on as well where
people just believe
all of this dumb
and it's not it's not rational it's
emotional
um so i mean i you know
again my skin in the game here is that i
want to live forever
and if we live in a society that starts
uh deciding science is stupid
and then you know well that's the end of
me living forever because let me tell
you about gold crosses and masks
sure won't make you live forever
kind of makes you wonder what the point
of progress is one day i'm gonna live in
a spaceship
man i'm gonna live in a spaceship
oh let's talk stargate
has it gotten better or worse over time
there's a lot of stupid people in the
past
i don't know i mean that might be an
interesting thing to explore in a stream
sometime
the flynn effect has largely stopped um
and the world is more complicated now
than it ever was so it may not be
that even if people are getting smarter
if the world's getting more complex at a
faster rate
like when you lived in the world when
you lived in like the forest
like there wasn't much
uh common sense worked really well
in today's world common sense may not
work so well anymore and we may have to
use science so we may have to use
rationality
um one of the judge dread comments
people can afford to be stupid i mean
that's another thing too
right like if you have um if people are
being supported
uh you know by
the the baseline for whether people
could survive in the past was like did
they understand
how to like hunt and eat and then grow
food and do
like practical things today what does it
take to survive
well you know you got to convince other
people to like
give you basically i mean that's
the economy um and it turns out you can
get big clusters of people
who like uh this is that
this is an interesting thing to go into
too like where does where does uh
where does wealth actually come from um
and
i might take always on it as like you
have people like baristas and
shoeshiners who don't create any value
um they don't i mean i'm not saying
they're useless but they don't actually
create any value you can't have an
economy full of baristas and shoeshiners
and then you have people like farmers
and miners who create linear value
right like like for every uh for every
acre of land you cultivate
you get it's linear right for every ton
of ore you mine it's linear
um and then there are these these these
uh like like squared effect people
who build technology right if you build
technology if you build a washing
machine
that if you build a washing machine that
automatically washes the clothes that
now takes five minutes of human labor
versus three hours of human labor you
freed up all of this time and you're
making things more efficient but you
can't entirely have that
if you don't have the linear base if you
have nothing that you're making more
efficient it doesn't help you at all
mimetics and genetics are now forever
intertwined medic fitness is not
necessarily ideal
um it is so
my hypothesis on college is
it teaches to the level of the average
you can't put sixty percent of the
population through college
what you get is a dumbing down of
college right
the sixth the bell curve applies no
matter what the bell curve will always
apply to any population
right um so if you've
increased the number of people who go to
college i don't think you've made
everybody smarter i think you've made
college dumber
um but yeah all right that's my end of
stream rant
you have to use the new spare time
widely well you know one of my favorite
and i'll leave you guys with this
this is one of my favorite uh my
favorite videos
um humans
need not apply what do you do in the
future when humans are not just
unemployed
but they're unemployable
all right yeah i got i got things to do
i got things to do that aren't the
stream
i just want to do a quick update on
coronavirus
walk around with boxers on your face you
look cool uh
thank you all for watching
no no no i think i think this is this is
it for uh
a bit um
goodbye goodbye thank you all for
watching